Guide to the Mary Thaw Thompson Papers, 1880-1928
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Mary Thaw Thompson Papers
1880-1928
Thompson, Mary Thaw, 1856-1944
1.3 cubic feet (5 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Material pertaining to Vassar College, the Association of Collegiate Alumnae, and the Association to Aid Scientific Research by Women.
Biographical Note
Mary Thaw Thompson (1856-1944), daughter of capitalist and philanthropist William Thaw, was born in Pittsburgh, PA. She was graduated from Vassar in 1877, and two years later married William Reed Thompson, a banker. The Thompsons had five daughters, three of whom attended Vassar. Mrs. Thompson was twice president of the Associate Alumnae of Vassar College and served as an alumnae trustee of the college. With Mary Morris Pratt she was a donor of the Vassar Chapel. In addition, Mrs. Thompson generously responded to the college's varied needs, large and small. Many of Mrs. Thompson's gifts reflect her interest in religion, art, and music. She was also a supporter of the Assoication of Collegiate Alumnae and the Association to Aid Scientific Research by Women. In her response to the questionnare for the Alumnae Biographical Register, Mrs. Thompson described herself well; she wrote, "No place on this questionnare for a gentlewoman serving her generation without publicity in civic, benevolent, and social organizations."
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, minutes, reports, financial records, and other items pertaining to Vassar College alumnae matters, trustee duties, her donations to the Chapel, reunions of the Class of 1877, and her involvement with the Association of Collegiate Alumnae and the Association to Aid Scientific Research by Women. Correspondents include Charles Pratt, Mary Pratt (VC 1880), Mary L. Avery (VC 1868), Mary Augusta Jordan (VC1876); Ella McCaleb (VC 1878), James Monroe Taylor, and Henry Noble MacCracken.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar College Photograph Files (4 photographs)
Vassar College Student Materials Collection
Vassar College Alumnae Collection (publications)
Henry Noble MacCracken Papers — Correspondence with Alumnae
Henry Noble MacCracken Papers — Correspondence with Trustees
Subject Headings
Names:
Avery, Mary L.; Jordan, Mary A. (Mary Augusta), 1855-1941; McCaleb, Ella, 1856-1933; Pratt, Mary; Pratt, Charles; Taylor, James Monroe, 1848-1916; MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-1970
Organizations:
Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Vassar College. Board of Trustees; Vassar College. Chapel; Vassar College. Class of 1877; Association of Collegiate Alumnae (U.S.); Association to Aid Scientific Research by Women
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
VCL Categories
Vassar College Trustees
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, April 2007.
Acquisition Information
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, (Boxes 1-2)
- Series II. Vassar College Administrative Material, (Boxes 3-5)
- Series III. Printed Materials, (Box 5)
Container List
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Chapel/organ (chiefly, Charles and Mary Pratt), 1901-1905 (Folder 1.1)
  - Chapel/organ, 1924-1927 (Folder 1.2)
  - President James Monroe Taylor, [1892-1909] (Folder 1.3)
  - President Henry Noble MacCracken, [1916-1937], n.d. (Folder 1.4)
  - General Vassar, [1880-1920] (Folder 1.5)
  - General Vassar, 1929-1923 (Folder 1.6)
  - General Vassar, 1924 (Folder 1.7)
  - General Vassar, 1925 (Folder 1.8)
  - General Vassar, 1926 (Folder 1.9)
  - General Vassar, 1927, 1928, n.d. (Folder 1.10)
  - Vassar friends, 1890-1899 (Folder 2.11)
  - Vassar friends, 1900-1907 (Folder 2.12)
  - Vassar friends, 1908-1919 (Folder 2.13)
  - Vassar friends, 1920-1925 (Folder 2.14)
  - Vassar friends (including 50th reunion of V.C. Class of 1877), 1926, 1927 (Folder 2.15)
  - Vassar friends, 1928, 1929, 1934, n.d. (Folder 2.16)
  - Association to Aid Scientific Research by Women, 1929, 1925 (Folder 2.17)
  - Other associations, [1902-1925] (Folder 2.18)
  - Family, 1904, 1925 (Folder 2.19)
  - Condolence letters to Elizabeth Thompson Reed after Mary Thaw Thompson's death (Folder 2.20)
  - Non-Vassar friends, [1910-1939] (Folder 2.21)
- Series II. Vassar College Administrative Material
  - Board of Trustees minutes, including some Executive Committee minutes and reports, 1921-1923 (Folder 3.22)
  - Board of Trustees minutes, 1924-1925 (Folder 3.23)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, 1926 (Folder 3.24)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, 1927 (Folder 3.25)
  - Copy of Mary Thaw Thompson's letter of resignation from the Board of Trustees (Folder 3.26)
  - President's reports to the Board of Trustees, 1921-1927 (Folder 3.27)
  - Reports of the Joint Committee on Faculty Insurance to me Board of Trustees, 1924-1925 (Folder 3.28)
  - Reports of Trustees' Committee on Faculty and Studies, 1923-1927 (Folder 4.29)
  - Reports of Trustees' Endowment Comittee, 1923, 1927, n.d. (Folder 4.30)
  - Reports of Trustees' Committee on the Library, 1925, 1927 (Folder 4.31)
  - Reports of ad to Trustees' Committees on Religious Life at Vassar, 1925-1926, n.d. (Folder 4.32)
  - Report of the Committee on Nominations to the Board of Trustees, 1926 (Folder 4.33)
  - Report of the Committee on Buildings to the Board of Trustees, 1926 (Folder 4.34)
  - Report of the Committee on Museum and Laboratories to the Board of Trustees, 1925 (Folder 4.35)
  - Reports of and to the Trustees' Committee on Euthenics, 1923, 1926, 1927, n.d. (Folder 4.36)
  - Reports (and related material) of the Committee on Grounds to the Board of Trustees, 1922-1924, 1926, 1927 (Folder 4.37)
  - Reports of the Trustees' Committee on Art and Art Collections, 1924-1925, 1927 (Folder 4.38)
  - Reports of the Committee on Household Management, 1925-1927 (Folder 4.39)
  - Report to the Trustees' Committee on Music, 192? (Folder 4.40)
  - Report to the Committee of Women Trustees of Vassar College, n.d. (Folder 4.41)
  - Report of the Alumnae House Management Committee, 1924 (Folder 4.42)
  - Report of the Trustees' Committee on Investments and Finance (Folder 4.43)
  - Report of the Trustees' Committee on Budget, (incomplete), 1923 (Folder 4.44)
  - Report of Trustees' Emergency Committee, (incomplete), n.d. (Folder 4.45)
  - Reports of the General Manager and Consulting Engineer, 1925-1927 (Folder 4.46)
  - Report of the Faculty Committee on Commencement Program, [1927] (Folder 4.47)
  - Financial reports, 1920-1921, 1921-1922 (Folder 5.48)
  - Financial reports, 1922-1923 (Folder 5.49)
  - Financial reports, 1923-1924 (Folder 5.50)
  - Financial reports, 1924-1925 (Folder 5.51)
  - Financial reports, 1924-1926 (Folder 5.52)
  - Financial reports, 1926-1927 (Folder 5.53)
- Series III. Printed Materials
  - A.A.V.C. reports (Folder 5.54)
  - Vassar Class of 1877 (Folder 5.55)
  - Vassar Chapel (Folder 5.56)
  - Associations (Folder 5.57)
  - Biographical information, including obituaries (Folder 5.58)
  - Miscellaneous family (Folder 5.59)